<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>continuous deployment on Philip Heltweg</title>
    <link>https://rhazn.com/tags/continuous-deployment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in continuous deployment on Philip Heltweg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rhazn.com/tags/continuous-deployment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deploy an app into your personal cloud</title>
      <link>https://rhazn.com/posts/deploy-an-app-into-your-personal-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rhazn.com/posts/deploy-an-app-into-your-personal-cloud/</guid>
      <description>As the final step in this long series of blogposts we are going to deploy a simple webapp in a docker container to my personal cloud. For context here is the personal cloud setup with Traefik/Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt (Run a personal cloud with Traefik, Let&amp;rsquo;s encrypt and Zookeeper).
In previous blogposts I also described how I built the app (Build a PWA in docker).
App deployment The deployment runs the docker container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a docker image on gitlab ci and publish it to google container registry</title>
      <link>https://rhazn.com/posts/build-a-docker-image-on-gitlab-ci-and-publish-it-to-google-container-registry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rhazn.com/posts/build-a-docker-image-on-gitlab-ci-and-publish-it-to-google-container-registry/</guid>
      <description>In previous blogposts I explained my concept of a personal cloud for my own projects (Kubernetes for Sideprojects) and how I set it up (Run a personal cloud with Traefik, Let&amp;rsquo;s encrypt and Zookeeper). I also showed how I packaged a PWA project with docker (Build a PWA in docker).
With all those ingredients ready to go the last hurdle to solve is building the docker image automatically as well as publishing it to a private container registry so I can deploy it to my cloud from there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy to google kubernetes engine using gitlab ci</title>
      <link>https://rhazn.com/posts/deploy-to-google-kubernetes-engine-using-gitlab-ci/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rhazn.com/posts/deploy-to-google-kubernetes-engine-using-gitlab-ci/</guid>
      <description>In a previous blogpost I showed how I build and publish docker images on gitlab ci (Build a docker image on gitlab ci)
Make sure to read that post first for an overview and permission setup.
Update the kubernetes service with the new docker image You can easily set up a deploy step using google&amp;rsquo;s own cloud SDK docker images. Note the service account with the permissions to change the kubernetes setup is saved as &amp;ldquo;GCLOUD_K8S_KEY&amp;rdquo; variable here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy a personal blog with Hugo, Firebase and Gitlab</title>
      <link>https://rhazn.com/posts/deploy-a-personal-blog-with-hugo-firebase-and-gitlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rhazn.com/posts/deploy-a-personal-blog-with-hugo-firebase-and-gitlab/</guid>
      <description>Blog requirements I recently evaluated what how writing content and carving out a little personal space on the internet would look like for me and came up with a list of requirements:
 Own my content (No third party platforms as only distribution method. There was a time before medium and there will be a time after medium.) Easy to set up and maintain (I don&amp;rsquo;t want to set up and host databases or complicated CMS systems and when I come back to this in a month it should be easy to update.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
