<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>research on Philip Heltweg</title>
    <link>https://heltweg.org/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in research on Philip Heltweg</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://heltweg.org/img/avatar2.jpeg</url>
      <link>https://heltweg.org/img/avatar2.jpeg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://heltweg.org/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AI-powered local interview transcription with Whisper</title>
      <link>https://heltweg.org/posts/whisper-ai-local-transcribe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heltweg.org/posts/whisper-ai-local-transcribe/</guid>
      <description>Transcribing interviews is tedious, let AI do the work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write an exposé for your thesis</title>
      <link>https://heltweg.org/posts/thesis-expose-project-outline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heltweg.org/posts/thesis-expose-project-outline/</guid>
      <description>Why write an exposé or project outline for your thesis and what to include.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenges to Open Collaborative Data Engineering</title>
      <link>https://heltweg.org/posts/challenges-to-open-collaborative-data-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heltweg.org/posts/challenges-to-open-collaborative-data-engineering/</guid>
      <description>Our paper &amp;ldquo;Challenges to Open Collaborative Data Engineering&amp;rdquo; got accepted to the Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences 2023 (HICSS 56). Sadly, we could not present in person due to a flight cancellation but we provided a short video presentation.
Abstract Open data is data that can be used, modified, and passed on, for free, similar to open-source software. Unlike open-source, however, there is little collaboration in open data engineering. We perform a systematic literature review of collaboration systems in open data, specifically for data engineering by users, taking place after data has been made available as open data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Softwarecampus 2022 - How to run a kickoff event for nerds</title>
      <link>https://heltweg.org/posts/swc-kickoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heltweg.org/posts/swc-kickoff/</guid>
      <description>How to run social events for nerds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master Thesis: Implementing a Structured Approach to Belief Revision by Deterministic Switching Between Total Preorders</title>
      <link>https://heltweg.org/posts/master-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heltweg.org/posts/master-thesis/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Belief change research investigates how agents adapt their knowledge with potentially conflicting information. A common formalization is by epistemic states, abstract entities often represented by faithful preorders. Operators describe how epistemic states change with new evidence and are classified by which postulates they satisfy. Different approaches have been suggested for the problem of iterated belief change. Recent work introduces uniform revision that revises an agent&amp;rsquo;s beliefs based on one static total preorder, therefore lowering representational costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Certification of Iterated Belief Changes via Model Checking and its Implementation</title>
      <link>https://heltweg.org/posts/certification-of-iterated-belief-changes-via-model-checking-and-its-implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heltweg.org/posts/certification-of-iterated-belief-changes-via-model-checking-and-its-implementation/</guid>
      <description>Note: An extended version of this paper has been published at the 7th Workshop on Formal and Cognitive Reasoning, you can find it here.
Our paper &amp;ldquo;Certification of Iterated Belief Changes via Model Checking and its Implementation&amp;rdquo; got accepted to the 19th International Workshop on Non-Monotonic Reasoning (NMR-2021) at the 18th International Conference on Principles of Knowledge Representation and Reasoning (KR 2021). During the workshop I held a short presentation of the results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Using Model Checking for the Certification of Iterated Belief Changes</title>
      <link>https://heltweg.org/posts/on-using-model-checking-for-the-certification-of-iterated-belief-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heltweg.org/posts/on-using-model-checking-for-the-certification-of-iterated-belief-changes/</guid>
      <description>Our paper &amp;ldquo;On Using Model Checking for the Certification of Iterated Belief Changes&amp;rdquo; got accepted to the 7th Workshop on Formal and Cognitive Reasoning (FCR-2021) at the 44th German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI-2021). During the workshop I held a short presentation of the results. You can find both the paper as well as the presentation slides here.
Abstract The theory of iterated belief change investigates how epistemic states are changed according to new beliefs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Of judges, aliens and total preorders</title>
      <link>https://heltweg.org/posts/judges-aliens-and-total-preorders/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heltweg.org/posts/judges-aliens-and-total-preorders/</guid>
      <description>Synopsis of some ideas from the paper &amp;#39;How to Revise a Total Preorder&amp;#39; by Booth and Meyer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning basics: Machine Learning by Stanford University (Coursera) review and notes</title>
      <link>https://heltweg.org/posts/machine-learning-basics-machine-learning-by-stanford-university-review-and-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heltweg.org/posts/machine-learning-basics-machine-learning-by-stanford-university-review-and-notes/</guid>
      <description>Review of the Machine Learning by Stanford University course on Coursera as well as notes</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
