<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>personal on Philip Heltweg</title>
    <link>https://heltweg.org/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in personal on Philip Heltweg</description>
    <image>
      <title>Philip Heltweg</title>
      <url>https://heltweg.org/img/avatar2.jpeg</url>
      <link>https://heltweg.org/img/avatar2.jpeg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://heltweg.org/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Talk: Not all those who wander are lost</title>
      <link>https://heltweg.org/posts/talk-not-all-those-who-wander-are-lost/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heltweg.org/posts/talk-not-all-those-who-wander-are-lost/</guid>
      <description>The following slides where created for my Talk &amp;ldquo;Not all those who wander are lost — Lessons from five years of learning and working remotely&amp;rdquo; for the Alumni Organisation of the Software Campus. They lose a lot of context without the actual talk but maybe they are of some interest.
Abstract After COVID, many knowledge workers have some experience with remote work. With more and more jobs going back to pre-pandemic setups, it is a good time to look back and reflect on what worked, what did not work and which best-practices support remote working while mitigating its downsides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank you reviewer 3</title>
      <link>https://heltweg.org/posts/thank-you-reviewer-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heltweg.org/posts/thank-you-reviewer-3/</guid>
      <description>Be friendly. Be like reviewer 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Softwarecampus 2022 - How to run a kickoff event for nerds</title>
      <link>https://heltweg.org/posts/swc-kickoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heltweg.org/posts/swc-kickoff/</guid>
      <description>How to run social events for nerds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who wrote this shit?</title>
      <link>https://heltweg.org/posts/who-wrote-this-shit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heltweg.org/posts/who-wrote-this-shit/</guid>
      <description>Trashing legacy software is fun. It creates camaraderie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master Thesis: Implementing a Structured Approach to Belief Revision by Deterministic Switching Between Total Preorders</title>
      <link>https://heltweg.org/posts/master-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heltweg.org/posts/master-thesis/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Belief change research investigates how agents adapt their knowledge with potentially conflicting information. A common formalization is by epistemic states, abstract entities often represented by faithful preorders. Operators describe how epistemic states change with new evidence and are classified by which postulates they satisfy. Different approaches have been suggested for the problem of iterated belief change. Recent work introduces uniform revision that revises an agent&amp;rsquo;s beliefs based on one static total preorder, therefore lowering representational costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to kill a dragon</title>
      <link>https://heltweg.org/posts/how-to-kill-a-dragon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heltweg.org/posts/how-to-kill-a-dragon/</guid>
      <description>How to slay a dragon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wisdom from the Internet, content that influenced how I think about software (and life).</title>
      <link>https://heltweg.org/posts/wisdom-from-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heltweg.org/posts/wisdom-from-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>A list of various content I found and gathered over the years that influenced me at the time or gave me new ideas. Mainly focused on software engineering and generic life advice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning basics: Machine Learning by Stanford University (Coursera) review and notes</title>
      <link>https://heltweg.org/posts/machine-learning-basics-machine-learning-by-stanford-university-review-and-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heltweg.org/posts/machine-learning-basics-machine-learning-by-stanford-university-review-and-notes/</guid>
      <description>Review of the Machine Learning by Stanford University course on Coursera as well as notes</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
